

Olha Shevchenko

Front End Developer (Angular), 28 years old

Ukraine, Kyiv

+38 096 29 37 844

☑ shev950@gmail.com

t.me/shevchenkolha

in linkedin.com/in/shevchenkolha

About me

I'm Front End Developer with 3+ years of experience since 2020. My core programming languages are JavaScript and TypeScript. I love to build modern web apps using OOP, SOLID, and the Angular framework. I always work on personal growth and my skills improvement.

Telegram: shevchenkolha

Scills

Technical Skills:

- JavaScript, TypeScript, Angular, NgRx, RxJS, Unit Testing, Next.js, HTML5, CSS3, SASS, jQuery, BEM, Flexbox, Perfect Pixel, Gulp, Git
- OOP, SOLID
- RESTful API, AJAX
- · Angular Material, Bootstrap

Soft Skills:

- · Agile/Scrum development methodology, Jira, Confluence, and other tools
- Mentoring, training
- Flexibility and focus on results

Domains:

• Gambling & iGaming, E-commerce, Landing Pages

Language

English - B2.

Work experience

Front End Developer

July 2020 - Present

Digicode (Kyiv, Ukraine)

Projects: LotteryHeroes, KayaMoola, Flybet, Supabets, GoldRush, Gbets, 10Bets, Backoffice

Period: September 2020 - Present

Description: SPA provides the chance to engage in the big lottery draws and engage in a diverse selection of non-lottery games to instantly win prizes. Built on Angular version 12.

Responsibilities:

- Feature development: this involves creating new Angular components, services, directives, or other Angular elements to implement new features in the application.
- Refactoring and improving existing code: improving code quality, ensuring adherence to coding standards, and fixing architectural or design issues.
- Bug fixing: identifying and fixing bugs in the frontend part of the application, which may involve analyzing stack traces, debugging, and testing fixes.
- Performance optimization: enhancing the performance of the frontend part of the application, optimizing page load times, and caching data or resources.

- Redesign: implementing new UI design, and creating new SCSS functions, mixins, and vars.
- Backend interaction: developing or integrating the frontend part with backend APIs, processing received data, and displaying it on the interface.
- Testing: writing and executing tests to verify the functionality of new features, identifying and fixing bugs.
- Documentation: writing code documentation, describing new features, and providing instructions on using components or services.
- Code reviews: actively participating in code reviews as both an author and a reviewer to identify issues, address shortcomings, and improve overall code quality.
- Researching new technologies and tools: Learning and implementing new tools, libraries, or frameworks that could improve front-end development.

Used technologies: JavaScript, Angular 4-12, TypeScript, OOP, SOLID, NgRx, RxJS, Unit Testing, Web Socket, SSR, ECMAScript, Git, HTML5, SCSS, Bootstrap 4, Flexbox, BEM.

Project: Lenders & Members

Period: February 2021 - October 2021

Description: SPA for purchasing and registration of cars in the USA. Built on Angular version 9.

Used technologies: JavaScript, Angular 9, TypeScript, OOP, SOLID, RxJS, ECMAScript, Git, GitFlow, HTML5, SCSS,

Bootstrap 4, Flexbox, BEM.

Project: BMM Comply

Period: July 2021 - September 2021

Description: SPA related to slot machines and audit. Built on Angular version 9.

Used technologies: JavaScript, Angular, TypeScript, OOP, SOLID, Angular Material, RxJS, ECMAScript, Git, GitFlow,

HTML5, SCSS, Bootstrap 4, Flexbox, BEM.

Project: Sorbet

Period: May 2021 - June 2021

Description: Landing page for Sorbet marketing company. Built on jQuery.

Used technologies: JavaScript, jQuery, AJAX, Git, GitFlow, HTML5, SCSS, Bootstrap 4, Flexbox, BEM, Perfect-Pixel.

Project: Digicode Internship **Period:** July 2021 - August 2021

Description: Landing page for Digicode Internship program. Built on jQuery.

Used technologies: JavaScript, jQuery, AJAX, Git, GitFlow, HTML5, SCSS, Bootstrap 4, Flexbox, BEM, Perfect-Pixel.

Project: Gemsoft

Period: July 2020 - September 2020

Description: Corporate website for games developer company. Built on NextJS.

Used technologies: JavaScript, Next.js, TypeScript, OOP, SOLID, Git, GitFlow, HTML5, SCSS, Bootstrap 4, Flexbox,

BEM, Perfect-Pixel.

HTML coder

February 2019 - February 2020

Imrev, (Khmelnytskyi, Ukraine)

Responsive web design and enhancement of existing websites of varying complexity.

Education

A2Lab

October 2018 - December 2018

Courses about HTML & CSS, Basic JavaScript.